Vincent Vo

Systems Administrator | Identity & Access Management | Automation & Security | ITSM linkedin.com/in/vovincent12 | vincenttyo.github.io

Professional Summary

Efficiency-driven IT Systems Administrator in Identity & Access Management automation, service delivery, user lifecycle management, and SaaS administration with tools such as Okta, Google Workspace, Slack, Workato, and APIs. Expertise in enforcing Zero Trust Policies, Role-Based Access Controls (RBAC), and Privileged Access Management (PAM) to enhance security posture. Proven success in implementing foundational ITSM programs, endpoint security (Kandji MDM, SentinelOne EDR), and SaaS integrations–enhancing corporate security, business, and user efficiency.

Core Competencies & Key Skills

- Identity & Access Management (IAM) & PAM: RBAC, Zero Trust, Adaptive MFA, SSO (SAML/OAuth)
- Automation & Scripting: Workato, BetterCloud, Python, Bash, REST APIs
- Administration & Security: Okta, Google Workspace, Microsoft 365, Kandji (MDM), SentinelOne (EDR)
- Lifecycle & ITSM: Provisioning, Onboarding/Offboarding, ServiceNow, Jira, Confluence, SCIM
- Security Operations: Access Reviews, Adaptive MFA, Network Segmentation, SSO Implementation
- Integration & Secrets Management: API Integrations, 1Password

Experience

IT Systems Administrator | Measurabl, San Diego, CA

May 2022 - Present

- Integrated third-party applications with Okta through authentication/authorization methods (SAML, OIDC, OAuth, SCIM). Automating IAM workflows, enabling SSO, automated provisioning and centralized authentication, reducing provisional errors by 67%.
- Administered, managed, and optimized core systems such as Okta, Google Workspace, Slack,
 Zoom through feature adoption, systems integrations using Workato (IPaaS), REST APIs, and scripts.
 Increasing operational efficiency by 25%.
- **Designed and drove implementation of RBAC, Device Trust, PAM policies** enhancing Zero Trust security, least privileged access, and reducing access requests by 50% for 200+ users.
- Adopted and enforced ITIL practices for service delivery as the sole IT SME including creating an
 Internal IT Help Desk, identifying SaaS optimization and waste, user support, and partnering with HR
 and business teams to align IT services with business needs.
- Managed device endpoints through Kandji, ABM, VPP. Enhancing endpoint security, moving on-prem
 management to outsourced by partnering with vendors and modernizing the process to support a
 global remote workforce.
- Achieved SOC2 Type 2 certification by monitoring Drata, collecting provisioned access evidence, auditing user permissions and alerts in Okta, Google Workspace, SentinelOne, and reviewing security policies.

Senior Service Desk Analyst | Realty Income, San Diego, CA

July 2020 - May 2022

Promoted to Senior Service Desk Analyst in December 2021 initially hired as a Service Desk Analyst. Taking on advanced responsibilities. Leading the Service Desk Team and development of ITIL and Security practices.

 Enforced least privileged access using Active Directory, Okta, and group policies, automating user provisioning, security management and following ITIL practices, reducing unauthorized access by 15%.

- Managed Microsoft 365, Active Directory, Okta, and group policies, optimizing SaaS integrations
 and access management, increasing system uptime and user productivity by 25%.
- Led a team of 5 improving ticket resolution by 25%, improving IT service delivery for end users.
- **Improved SOX audit compliance** by capturing evidence and audit logging, reducing audit friction and ensuring adherence to SOX controls.
- Managed PDQ Deploy for patch management for 200+ endpoints, automating security updates and maintaining system compliance.

Client Services Engineer | CARET (fka AbacusNext), San Diego, CA December 2018 - July 2020

- **Enhanced user experience for 300+ clients** by managing VMware Horizon virtual machines using Active Directory, group policies, patch management, and solving technical issues related to their used applications.
- Improved the efficiency of virtual machines for business client users by automating computer maintenance tasks with BAT scripts for disk drive cleaning, application management, and patch file removal.
- **Ensured satisfactory client issue resolution and optimized windows server performance** by collaborating with cloud engineers, providing exceptional service delivery.

Certifications

- BetterCloud Administrator | BetterCloud 2023
- ITIL 4 Strategist: Direct, Plan, and Improve | PeopleCert 2021
- ITIL 4 Foundation | PeopleCert 2021
- Google IT Support Professional | Coursera 2019

Education

Bachelor's in Interdisciplinary Studies (Kinesiology, Psychology, Sociology) | San Diego State University